

OLIVER SWITZER

United States

- ♠ Brooklyn, NY, United States
- യ www.oliverswitzer.com

About me

With 7 years of experience working with various server and client-side languages, I am looking to work with startups or large companies that are making a social, creative or environmental impact using technology. I enjoy learning from and mentoring other engineers through pairing, as well as advocating for extreme programming (XP) practices like test driven development and delivering value-proven software in short iterations. I also am a big proponent of Domain Driven Design (DDD) and applying SOLID object oriented principles to the software that I write. With that said, I am always looking to learn new languages and practices and continue expanding my area of expertise.

Technical Skills

Work experience



Senior Software Engineer

06/2018 - 05/2020

Kickstarter, Brooklyn, NY, United States

Performed technical lead responsibilities; collaborated with product and design to break down work for myself and teammates, mentored other engineers and built out critical infrastructure

- Planned and implemented Kickstarter's new signup and checkout experience that increased completed checkouts by 4%, roughly \$1M in annual revenue
- Supported our iOS and Android native app teams through building out APIs and building cross-platform features
- Built out scalable ETL process for replicating and sanitizing our production payments database
- Developed support tools to improve communication during site outages, as well as a UI that aggregates and categorizes site incidents to find trends

Software Engineer

08/2015 - 05/2018

Pivotal, Brooklyn, NY, United States

Act as engineering lead on multiple projects, involving conveying core domain to rest of team, scheduling one-on-ones with individual team members and facilitating communication between development team and client stakeholders

- Worked in multiple product contexts (finance, health care, charity, education), to deliver full-stack features
- Actively participated in and helped plan user research sessions, as well as technical discovery into new product domains
- Helped identify what new client projects and employees Pivotal will take on
- Facilitate weekly retrospectives, iteration planning meetings and office-wide discussions about core XP/LEAN/Agile practices and values

Work experience

Software Engineer

08/2014 - 06/2015

littleBits, Brooklyn, NY, United States

Third engineering hire; hit the ground running with small balanced team to deliver both front and back end feature work

- Created a crowdsourcing voting app, that uses state machine logic to track circuit ideas that are voted upon and curated
- Helped start NYC's first official React Meetup hosted at the littleBits office
- · Worked with React to create first interactive littleBits circuit simulator
- Built out RESTful mobile app API endpoints
- Increased on site performance by 17% using Redis-backed view caching

Software Engineer

04/2014 - 07/2014

HowAboutWe, Brooklyn, NY, United States

Implemented full stack features for product team in charge of "HowAboutWe for singles" application

- Worked in Rails stack with Backbone/SASS/HAML, and TDD (RSpec & Capybara) when writing code for both front and back-end site functionality in
- · Worked with extensive Memcached-based caching system
- Created models that implement worker queues for sending SMS to users using Twilio API

Education

Software Engineering

02/2014 - 06/2014

The Flatiron School, Brooklyn, NY

Physics 09/2009 - 05/2013

Bard College, Annandale-on-Hudson, NY, United States

Received a full-ride Distinguished Scientist Scholarship (DSS)

Hobbies



Writing Music



Cooking



Gardening



Surfing & Swimming



Hiking